## Anirudh Patil

Sr Automation Engineer (DevOps / Ansible Tower)

## Contact

#### **Address**

Bengaluru, KA, 560086

#### **Phone**

968 658 8883

#### E-mail

anirudhpatilmca@gmail.co

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anirudh-patil-a3a9655a

## **Skills**

**AWS** 

Very Good

**Jenkins** 

Good

**ELK** 

Good

Grafana & Prometheus

Very Good

**Nagios** 

Very Good

Dynatrace

**Average** 

Enthusiastic Sr Automation Engineer (DevOps / Ansible Tower) with 7 Years Experience, eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in IT Industry.

## **Work History**

2017-06 -2021-05

# Sr Automation Engineer ( DevOps / Ansible Tower )

Integra Micro Software Services - IMSS, Bangalore, KARNATAKA

#### Client - RedHat

Developed multiple POC's on **Redhat Ansible Tower** use cases as per clients requests & be a part of presales meeting with Redhat & its clients

#### Client - Samsung R&D Institute

Worked as **Cloud Operations Engineer** to manage AWS Infrastructure for **"Samsung Pay"** Application

- Majorly involved in Configuring/Maintaining Monitoring Systems using Open Source Tools for Production environment on AWS Cloud
- Used Nagios Core for basic alerting systems like service health checks & Nodes reachability
- Implemented Grafana for Visual Dashboards of services & Applications, mainly for services on Static IP's
- Implemented Prometheus for Visual Dashboards of services & Applications on Dynamic Ip's & specially on Application Load Balancers / Databases Servers
- Worked on Dynatrace which uses the Purepath technology for tracking issues like 5xx/4xx failures & to drill down on specific Application URI's to detect Errors/Exceptions & affected IP's
- Used Kibana for trend analysis & to drill down logs with specific details & Time Stamps
- Used JIRA Ticketing tool to Report/Track issues & schedule Infrastructure Maintenances during Weekend/Non-Biz Hours
- Implemented Jenkins for activities on daily basis like triggering Pager Duty alerts for Regional On-Call support Engineers



2014-08 -2017-06

## Sr. Systems Admin Associate Consultant

NTT DATA Global Delivery Services Limited, Bangalore, KARNATAKA

#### Tier-2 Linux Administration:

- Maintaining the Users, Groups and Permissions.
- File System Administration and Disk Management.
- Advanced File Permissions and Access Control List.
- Package management using RPM and YUM.
- Installing and Configuring of DHCP, DNS, FTP, Services.
- Configuring and Managing NFS
- Configuration of remote applications ssh, rsh
- Used HP-ILO to control and monitor HP ProLiant and Blade servers from a remote location.
- Manage Linux Servers during performance issues and power down's.
- Following up with Vendors like Maintech, IBM, HP to replace faulty hardware's.
- Perform various health checks on the servers to keep them healthy.
- Coordinating with technical teams for updates on Incident, Change and Problem Request.
- Seeking updates and approval for all types of changes viz. Standard/normal Changes, planned changes, Emergency Changes
- It involves regular interaction/communication with top managers and clients in California and Develop an understanding of the clients organizational and infrastructure environment
- Chasing tickets to make sure it reaches right resolver group and issue is resolved within stipulated resolution time based on severity (Maintaining SLA).
- Drive group chats
- Used SERVICE NOW Ticketing tool to Report/Track issues & schedule Infrastructure Maintenances during Weekend/Non-Biz Hours

## **Education**

2021-06 -2023-07 Master of Computer Applications: Computer Science & IT (Currently Pursuing Online)

Jain (Deemed-to-be University) - Bangalore

2011-09 - Bachelor of Computer Applications: Computer Science - 73.9%

Bangalore University

## **Certifications**

2016-12	Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) - Certification ID: 160-267-761
2018-06	AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate - Certification ID: N4ZTOSS2BMQ4Q7WX
2018-06	ITIL Foundation - Certification ID : GR750424182AP

## **Technical Trainings**

- Graduate Student @Edureka (Cloud Architect Masters/Devops Program) which was for 3 months
- NTT DATA Associate Training (3 Months)
- SAMSUNG WORKSHOP on ElasticSearch, LogStash & Kibana (ELK)

## **Conferences Attended**

IEEE Bangalore International Conference on Antenna Innovations and Modern Technologies (iAIM-2017)